Guide to the Jonathan Edwards College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Jonathan Edwards College, Yale University, records of the master
1930-1965
RU 592
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
13.25
(18 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, appointments, contracts, applications, minutes, permissions, diplomas, recommendations, and student records documenting student life and affairs, personnel, finances, and activities of the master of Jonathan Edwards College, Yale University.
Jonathan Edwards College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-H-2 (YRG 13-H-2), Records of the master of Jonathan Edwards College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, appointments, contracts, applications, minutes, permissions, diplomas, recommendations, and student records documenting student life and affairs, personnel, finances, and activities of the master of Jonathan Edwards College, Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
College students; Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Employees; Jonathan Edwards College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Student records for the Classes of 1934-1959, 1930-1959; Accession 19ND-A-250
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036.
  - Class of 1934
  - Class of 1935
  - Class of 1936
  - Class of 1937
  - Class of 1938
  - Class Of 1939
  - Class of 1940
  - Class of 1941
  - Class of 1942
  - Class of 1943
  - Class of 1944
  - Class of 1945
  - Class of 1946
  - Class of 1947
  - Class of 1948
  - Class of 1949
  - Class of 1950
  - Class of 1951
  - Class of 1952
  - Class of 1953
  - Class of 1954
  - Class of 1955
  - Class of 1956
  - Class of 1957
  - Class of 1958
  - Class of 1959
- Subject files, circa 1950-1965; Accession 1965-A-003
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2041.
  - Academic Records, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 5)
  - Activities Lists, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 8)
  - Alumni Board Correspondence, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Athletics, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 16)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 17 - 22)
  - Bills Paid, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 23 - 24)
  - Bills, Statements, 1956-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25 - 32)
  - Bulletin Board, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 33 - 35)
  - Bursary, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 36 - 38)
  - Bursary Appointments and Contracts, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 39 - 41)
  - Bursary Contracts, 1955-1959 (Box 3, Folder 42 - 44)
  - Calendar of Events, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 45 - 46)
  - Career Counseling, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Celebration 250t h Anniversary, 1951 October 19 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Checks Cancelled, 1955-1960 (Box 3, Folder 49 - 54)
  - Christmas Funds, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 55 - 56)
  - Classes of, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 57 - 64)
  - Class Reunions, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Clubs, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Coat and Tie Rule, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 67 - 68)
  - College, the, 1950-1955 (Box 4, Folder 69 - 72)
  - College Aide Applicants Class of 1961, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - College Aide Applicants, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - College Correspondence, 1952-1959 (Box 4, Folder 75 - 79)
  - College Council, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 80 - 82)
  - College Outing, 1951-1956 (Box 4, Folder 83 - 87)
  - College Weekend, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 88 - 89)
  - Committee, Library, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Committee on Teaching Fellows, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Committee,Undergraduate Affairs, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Council of Masters
    - Appointments of Fellows, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 93 - 94)
    - Chairmanship, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 96 - 98)
  - Minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 99 - 100)
  - Permissions, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 101 - 102)
  - counselor Assignments Class of, 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 103 - 108)
  - Dances, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 109 - 113)
  - Debating, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Deans List, 1956-1959 (Box 6, Folder 115 - 116)
  - Dining Hall, 1954-1959 (Box 6, Folder 117 - 120)
  - Dinner
    - Birthday, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Christmas, 1955-1958 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Senior Class, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 124 - 128)
    - Sophomore Class, 1952-1957 (Box 6, Folder 129 - 132)
  - Diplomas, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - English Universities (Goodhart, Corpus Christi), 1955-1957 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Entertainment, 1948-1956 (Box 6, Folder 135 - 139)
  - Examination Schedules, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Appointments for Reservations of Fellows, 1940-1956 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Fellows' Appointments, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Committee on Fellows, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Fellows' lists, 1954-1959 (Box 7, Folder 144 - 145)
    - Fellows' Notices, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 146 - 148)
    - Fellows' Offices, 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 149 - 150)
    - Resident Fellows, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Funds, loans, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Fund, Master's, 1955-1961 (Box 7, Folder 154 - 159)
  - Fund, J.E. College special, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 160 - 162)
  - Guards, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Guest Suite, 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Graduates returning, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Honors and Prizes, 1952-1957 (Box 8, Folder 167 - 171)
  - Hospital Infirmary List, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Hoyt Fellowship, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Jesters, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 175 - 176)
  - Labor - Management Club Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Lectures (J.C.R.), 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Maintenance Budgets, 1952-1956 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Majors, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 180 - 181)
  - Master William H. Dunham - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Navy, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Navy - ROTC Unit, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Notices, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 186 - 188)
  - Office Aides' Schedules, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 189 - 190)
  - Personnel, 1936-1956 (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - Personnel - Secretary, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - Police, 1956-1958 (Box 9, Folder 198)
  - Police, campus, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 199)
  - Property Maintenance, 1956-1958 (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - Readmissions, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 201 - 203)
  - Recommendations
    - 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - 1952-1956 (Box 9, Folder 205 - 206)
    - Graduate School, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 207 - 208)
    - Undergraduate, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Record Collection, 1944-1947 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Religious Activities, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Requisitions, 1952-1956 (Box 9, Folder 212 - 215)
  - Requisitions, 1956-1962 (Box 10, Folder 216 - 220)
  - Roman Orgy, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 221)
  - Room Allocations, 1952-1957 (Box 10, Folder 222 - 225)
  - Room Assignments, 1951-1959 (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Room Inspection, 1952-1959 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Room Keys, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 228)
  - Scholarship, 1952-1956 (Box 11, Folder 229)
  - School of Engineering, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 230)
  - Snack Bar, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 231)
  - Special Accounts, Fellows Fund, 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 232)
  - Student Directories, 1952-1959 (Box 11, Folder 233)
  - Student Information Sheet, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Student Lists, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 235)
  - Student Organizations, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 236)
  - Students and Rooms, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Telephones, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 239)
  - Television, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 240)
  - Television and Workshop, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 241)
  - Undergraduates Staying after May, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 242)
  - The University Council, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 243)
  - Warning Lists, 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 244)
  - Workshop, 1954-1957 (Box 11, Folder 245)